河南省二零二五年初中学业水平。
行考试英语。
一，听力理解。
第一节，听下面五段对话，
每段对话后有一个小题，
从题中所给的
,B 1. Hi, Tom.
三个选项中选出最佳答案。
每段对话读两遍。
How about going for a walk this evening?
Sorry, but I'm going to draw pictures.
Hi, Tom. How about going for a walk this evening?
2. Hello, can I help you?
Yes, how much is the school bag?
Let me check.
It's 100 yuan.
Okay, I'll take it.
Hello, can I help you?
Yes, how much is the school bag?
Let me check.
It's 100 yuan.
Okay, I'll take it.
3. I like playing volleyball and basketball.
What about you, Tony?
I like basketball too, but my favorite is baseball.
I like playing volleyball and basketball.
What about you, Tony?
I like basketball too, but my favorite is baseball.
4. The rain is quite heavy, isn't it?
Yeah, I was in a hurry and I forgot my umbrella today.
I have one.
We can share it.
The rain is quite heavy, isn't it?
Yeah, I was in hurry and I forgot my umbrella today.
I have one.
We can share it.
5. Hello, Bella.
What do you think of the book?
It's wonderful and I've learned a lot about Chinese food.
Hello, Bella. What do you think of the book?
It's wonderful and I've learned a about Chinese food.
2. A, B, and the sixth to the seventh two questions.
第二节，听下面几段对话或独白，
每段对话或独白后有几个小题。
从题中所给的
三个选项中选出最佳答案。
每段对话或独白读两遍。
听下面一段对话，回答。
Saturday is finally coming.
what a nice day.
So it is, and I think we should help Mom do the house cleaning today, okay?
Oh no, I just want to play basketball with my friends.
Come on, what do you want to do?
Take out the rubbish or clean the windows?
I prefer to take out the rubbish.
Good, go and collect all the rubbish.
Oh, so much.
Don't worry, I'll help you with it later.
Saturday is finally coming.
Yeah, what a nice day.
So it is, and I think we should help Mom do the house cleaning today, okay?
Oh no, I just want to play basketball with my friends.
Come on, what do you want to do?
Take out the rubbish or clean the windows?
I prefer to take out the rubbish.
Good, go and collect all the rubbish.
Oh, so much.
Don't worry, I'll help you with it later.
听下面一段对话，回答第八至第九两个小题。
Hi Jin, where are you going?
Hi David, I'm going to see Alice with Judy.
I went to the hospital to see Alice yesterday.
She was a little better and will be back to school in two days.
Do we need to take a bus there?
No, it's not far from our school.
Okay, we'll walk there.
Hi Jin, where are you going?
Hi David, I'm going to see Alice with Judy.
I went to the hospital to see Alice yesterday.
She was a little better and will be back to school in two days.
Do we need to take a bus there?
No, it's not far from our school.
Okay, we'll walk there.
Listen Good morning, everyone.
听下面一段。
读白，回答第十至第十二三个小题。
I'm your guide today.
I'm so happy to show you around my hometown.
As you can see, it's a beautiful village with clear rivers and green mountains.
In the morning, we'll climb the mountains and enjoy the beauty of nature.
At three o in the afternoon, we'll set off to pick tea leaves for family.
At five o we'll make paper cuttings.
My village is famous for this traditional art.
Then we'll try the special noodles here.
And the singing and dancing show will begin at eight o in the evening.
Hope you will enjoy your stay here.
morning, everyone. I'm your guide today.
I'm so happy to show you around my hometown.
As you can see, it's a beautiful village with clear rivers and green mountains.
In the morning, we'll climb the mountains and enjoy the beauty of nature.
At three o in the afternoon, we'll set off to pick tea leaves for fun.
At five o we'll make paper cuttings.
My village is famous for this traditional art.
Then we'll try the special noodles here.
And the singing and dancing show will begin at eight o in the evening.
Hope you will enjoy your stay here.
听下面一段对话，回答第十三至第十五三个小题。
Peter, what are you listening to?
Rock music. Do you like it?
Yes, it makes me excited.
What about you?
I like country music.
Nice. How long have you been in love with it?
Six years. Do you always like country music?
Not really. When I was little, I didn't listen to it at all.
So, when did you become interested in it?
I started playing the piano at the age of That was when I took an interest in it.
第三节，你将听到一则活动通知，
请用你所听到的内容填写表格中所缺单词。
每。
每空线填一词或一个数字。
短文读两遍。
Attention please. is some information about English Corner for the students in Grade
7. English Corner starts this Friday.
It is every Friday from 5 o to 6 o in afternoon.
You can join in at the square in front of the library.
Our foreign teachers will be there too.
You can practice English in a fun way.
You can ask questions, share stories,
talk about hobbies, or learn about different cultures.
All of the students in Grade 7 are welcome.
Just come and have fun.
Don't worry if your English isn't perfect.
Get together to love, learn, and make new friends.
Thank you. Attention please.
Here is some information about English Corner for the students in Grade 7.
English Corner starts this Friday.
It is every Friday from 5 o to 6 o in the afternoon.
You can join in at the square in front of the library.
Our foreign teachers will be there too.
You can practice English in a fun way.
You can ask questions, share stories, talk about hobbies, or learn about different
cultures. All of the students in Grade 7 are welcome.
Just come and have fun.
Don't worry if your English isn't perfect.
Get together to love, learn, and make new friends.
Thank you.
请同学们将第一至第十五小题的答案
填涂在答题卡上，并。
将第十六至第二十小题的答案
填写在答题卡相应位置。
听力考试到此结束，请同学们
继续答题。